Riccardo Lincetto

Practical problem solver in the fields of Computer Vision, Machine and Deep Learning. Particularly interested in Neuromorphic technologies and Astronomy. Academic background in Telecommunications and Electrical Engineering (ICT). Experienced in data collection, management and visualisation. Life-long learner.

Also available as contractor, freelancer or consultant.

Contacts:

riccardo.lincetto@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Riccardo Lincetto

EXPERIENCE

Extra projects - Freelancer

February 2022 - now

Visual defect detection from image segmentation (data pipeline, model training); object detection for drone warehouse applications (data synthesis, training, on-device deployment, c++ inference post-processor); design and on-premise deployment of LLM-based RAG system.

Machine Learning Engineer - <u>CGTrader</u>

February 2022 - November 2024 / Vilnius 📂

Generative AI research for 3D (text-to-3d, image-to-3d) and integration into <u>cgdream.ai</u>; early-stage BE design and build of <u>cgdream.ai</u>; at-scale image classification and aesthetics ranking projects; custom deployment process of ML models (containers, custom registry, API).

Computer Vision Engineer - Sportradar

October 2021 - December 2021 / Ljubljana 📁

Research on neural style transfer, from simulation to reality, and tests on data augmentation.

Computer Vision Engineer - <u>Dronus</u>

September 2019 - September 2021 / Trieste 🔲

Research and prototyping of computer vision and learning-based algorithms for drones navigation and applications. Work on optical flow and object detection on resource constrained settings. Sensors research for system design. Mechanical parts control on Arduino.

Computational Imaging Intern - Sony

September 2018 - March 2019 / EuTEC, Stuttgart

Internship and Master Thesis on multispectral data acquisition with eventbased cameras. Use of events obtained from a spectral filter tuning to reconstruct the spectrum of the scene. Sensor tests and benchmark evaluation with simple reconstruction methods.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PyTorch, OpenCV; ROS; SQL, pandas;

Python, C++, Java;

Linux, Shell, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS;

LLM / GPT applications, imaging sensors.

LANGUAGES

Italian - mother tongue

English - proficient

German - basic

HOBBIES

Volleyball, reading, learning, chess, cultural exchange.

EDUCATION

MEng @ UNIPD (Padua) Telecommunications
Oct 2016 - Apr 2019
Score: 110 cum Laude / 110

BEng @ UNIPD (Padua) Information Technology
Oct 2013 - Nov 2016
Score: 98 / 110